William Sebastian David Alexander Full Stack Developer

Contact Number: 07568144268
williama149@gmail.com
GitHub: github.com/wsdalex

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/william-alexander-aba503185/

Date of Birth: 27/02/1997

About Me

I am an ambitious software developer based in the London area. Having recently graduated Maker Academy, I am a strong programmer with a foundation in TDD and OOP. I am keen to embrace new technologies and always drive myself to learn more. I pride myself in my social skills. I often find myself able to comfortably adapt to new teams and new environments. Having worked in a broad set of industries, I enjoy throwing myself in the deep end and learning quickly about new work practices. I also have a strong moral attitude towards my work. I want my work to have a positive impact on the world and people I work with. My goal is to grow as a developer and always deliver high quality work reliably.

Technical Experience

- Front-End Development: React, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, SwiftUI
- Back-End Development: Node.js, Typescript, Express.js, Python, SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Mobile Development: Swift, SwiftUI, iOS Development
- Testing and QA Tools: Pytest, Jest, Playwright, CI/CD
- Tools and Practices: Git, Docker, Scrum Fundamentals, Test Drive Development

Projects

Makers BnB | Group Project

- Full stack application written in Python using Flask, Jinja and postgresql
- Functionally rich and attractive property booking website
- Users can view properties and make date specific bookings but also create properties to be made available.

Makers 64 | Group Project

- Full stack application written in the MERN stack.
- Games platform with multiple games and social media features
- Users can sign up, message and share their latest activity with friends
- Front end design inspired by Nintendo 64 and Miniclip

Man On | Solo Project

- Full stack application written with NodeJS, Express, Svelte and MongoDB
- Football data app with statistics on the latest competitions, teams, players and matches
- Express API that caches commonly requested data to limit external API calls
- Front end built in Svelte for reactivity and to experiment with different frontend frameworks

Professional Experience

Makers Academy

May 2024 - September 2024

- Graduate of Makers intensive and rigorous software engineer bootcamp
- Learned the value of fundamental coding principles such as TDD and OOP
- Created and implemented databases with complex schema
- Designed, planned and built multiple full stack apps as a group following AGILE processes
- Became versatile with new technologies by learning multiple languages and frameworks

Location Marshall For Film and TV

September 2022 - November 2023

- Worked on films and TV with creators such as David Ayer and Jason Stathom
- Developed a strong ability in problem solving, adapting to everchanging set locations
- Expected to have a deep, detailed understanding of locations to ensure a smooth filming process
- Developed strong communicative relationships with multiple departments
- Charged with evaluating environmental impact of work and ways to mitigate it

Studio Production Assistant for Global Blue

September 2019 - July 2020

- Production assistant for in house Design team
- Charged with running and assisting the company production line
- Helped produce in house marketing materials, designs for outside partners (e.g Alipay) and business critical documents
- Liaised with both clients and designers to accurately deliver on any brief
- In charge of internal communication to effectively coordinate with other departments
- Managed the production time table to ensure team efficiency

Education and Qualifications

University of Leeds, Leeds, UK

2015 - 2018

- Successfully completed a BA in Philosophy
- Extensive analytical and evaluative skills required for study
- Further development of communication skills when required to complete group presentations

King Edward VI Aston School, Aston, Birmingham UK

2008 - 2015

- A level: ABB (History, Government and Politics, English Literature)
- 8 GCSE's A*-C (A in Maths and English Lit & Lang

Languages

English (Native)

References available upon request.